<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Edgar M.H. on Edgar Martín Hernández</title>
    <link>https://emartinher-PSEM3.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Edgar M.H. on Edgar Martín Hernández</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://emartinher-PSEM3.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://emartinher-PSEM3.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 19:50:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emartinher-PSEM3.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Peer-reviewed articles   Martín-Hernández, E., Hu, Y., Zavala, V., Martín, M. &amp;amp; Ruiz-Mercado, G. Analysis of incentive policies for phosphorus recovery at livestock facilities in the Great Lakes area. Resources, Conservation and Recycling 177, 105973 (2022). (link)
  Martín-Hernández, E., Martín, M. &amp;amp; Ruiz-Mercado, G. A geospatial environmental and techno-economic framework for sustainable phosphorus management at livestock facilities. Resources, Conservation &amp;amp; Recycling 175, 105843 (2021). (link)
  Mohammadi, M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://emartinher-PSEM3.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emartinher-PSEM3.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Current projects  Assessment of phosphorus releases and recycling alternatives in the agricultural sector  Techno-economic assessment of phosphorus recovery technologies (article 1, article 2, article 3 book chaper 1 book chaper 2 ) Decission-making framework for the selection of P recovery technologies (article 1) Incetive policies for promoting phosphorus recovery and recycling at livestock facilities (article 1)    Past projects  Centralized and decentralized systems for organic waste management (article 1) Production of polyols from sawdust: process design and scale-up study (article 1) Polysilicon refinery (article 1, article 2)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://emartinher-PSEM3.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emartinher-PSEM3.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Edgar Martín Hernández I am Ph.D. in Chemical Engineering, and I am concerned with assessing and improving the sustainability of current agricultural and industrial systems. I like to work in the intersection of environmental and sustainability fields with the decision-making and optimization techniques using open source software.
I started my bachelor in Chemical Engineering at the University of Salamanca (USAL) (Spain) in 2011, having the chance of performing an engineering internship at Michelin S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://emartinher-PSEM3.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emartinher-PSEM3.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>email: emaritnher@usal.es</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Software for ChemE</title>
      <link>https://emartinher-PSEM3.github.io/freesoftware/freesoftware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emartinher-PSEM3.github.io/freesoftware/freesoftware/</guid>
      <description>Free Software for ChemE Nowadays the use of software in Chemical Engineering is essential for many applications, from scientific and technical calculations to the design of presentations and preparation of documents. Currently, there are both free and proprietary alternatives to address the different tasks and challenges of the Chemical Engineering field. However Free Software is developed under political and ethical principles which promotes the expand of the open access knowledge, making scientific research more visible and accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julia</title>
      <link>https://emartinher-PSEM3.github.io/freesoftware/julia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emartinher-PSEM3.github.io/freesoftware/julia/</guid>
      <description>Julia Under construction</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://emartinher-PSEM3.github.io/freesoftware/latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emartinher-PSEM3.github.io/freesoftware/latex/</guid>
      <description>LaTeX  LaTeX is a platform for prepare documents specially oriented for scientific documents, with specific support for mathematical expressions.
To create a document in LaTeX a predefined type of text must be selected to determine the appropriate global format. The default styles are book, report, article and letter. The text in LaTeX is introduced as plain text, and different functions can be used to define the text format, include images, tables, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>https://emartinher-PSEM3.github.io/freesoftware/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emartinher-PSEM3.github.io/freesoftware/python/</guid>
      <description>Python  Python Python is an open source programming language created by Guido van Rossum in 1991. It is an interpreted high-level language, which enhances the readability of the code. This allows the user to create programs in an easier way and producing shorter codes than other programming languages. Python has a large user’s community whose provides support and creates packages, libraries and modules which extends the capabilities and applications of Python to areas such as scientific and engineering simulations, machine learning, computational chemistry, data visualization or its implementation in embedded systems, among others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
